uksmallbusinessdirectory.co.uk 2018-09-29

# UK Small Business Directory Privacy Policy

## UK Small Business Directory Privacy Policy

Please Note:  
All information submitted to the UK Small Business Directory is made publicly available.

This privacy policy sets out how "TJS Marketing Ltd." uses and protects any information that you give "TJS Marketing Ltd." when you use this website.

"TJS Marketing Ltd." is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

"TJS Marketing Ltd." may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from 01/05/2018.

### What we collect

We may collect the following information:

  * your name and the name of company

  * contact information including email address, telephone number, website address, social networking details.

  * demographic information such as street address, town, county, post code, country

  * the business description you provide us

  * any other information you provide to us

### What we do with the information we gather

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

  * Internal record keeping.

  * To publically display in our online business directory

  * We may use the information to improve our products and services.

  * We may periodically send promotional emails about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided.

  * From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by email, phone, fax or mail.

  * We may occasionally contact you by email, phone, fax or mail to offer you special offers, upgrade options and enhanced listings.

  * We may occasionally pass on your information and contact details to other businesses/individuals who provide marketing services.

  * As part of a sale of our assets or a merger of our company: We may in the future sell all or part of our assets or be involved in a merger. It is customary for user information to be included with the transferred assets in these types of transactions. However, we will take steps to assure that any personal information is used in a manner consistent with the terms under which it was collected.

### Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure if you no longer want your details made publically available we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

### How we use cookies

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about webpage traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

We also use 3rd party cookies from advertisers and specifically from the Google AdSense program. Most web browsers automatically accept these cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. Please consult the instructions in your web browser to find out how to control cookies.

Third parties may be placing and reading cookies on your browser, or using web beacons to collect information, in the course of ads being served on our website. Please consult the instructions in your web browser to find out how to control this behaviour

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

We also use 3rd party tracking systems to monitor visitor behaviour, the primary systems we use are statcounter.com and google analytics, please view the privacy policies of both ofthese companies if you have any concerns.

## Background:

This Policy applies as between you, the User of this Web Site and TJS Marketing Ltd the owner and provider of this Web Site.This Policy applies to our use of any and all Data collected by us in relation to your use of the Web Site and any Services or Systems therein. 

Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information which are downloaded to your device when you visit a website. Cookies are then sent back to the originating website on each subsequent visit, or to another website that recognises that cookie. Cookies are useful because they allow a website to recognise a user’s device. You can find more information about cookies at: [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) and [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) for a video about cookies visit [www.google.co.uk/safetycenter/](http://www.google.co.uk/safetycenter/) Cookies do lots of different jobs, like letting you navigate between pages efficiently, remembering your preferences, and generally improve the user experience. They can also help to ensure that adverts you see online are more relevant to you and your interests. 

  1. TJS Marketing Ltd may set and access first-party Cookies on your computer. Cookies that may be placed on your computer are detailed in Schedule 1 to this Policy.These Cookies are integral to the services provided by the Web Site to you.
  2. You can choose to enable or disable Cookies in your web browser.By default, your browser will accept Cookies, however this can be altered.For further details please consult the help menu in your browser. Disabling Cookies may prevent you from using the full range of Services available on the Web Site.
  3. You may delete Cookies, however you may lose any information that enables you to access the Web Site more quickly.
  4. The Web Site uses the third-party Cookies detailed in Schedule 2 to this Policy for the purposes described therein. These Cookies are not integral to the services provided by the Web Site to you and may be blocked at your choosing via your internet browser’s privacy settings. Please ensure that your internet browser is up-to-date and consult the help and guidance provided by the developer of your browser if you are unsure as to how to adjust your privacy settings.

### Schedule 1. First-Party Cookies

**Cookie** | **Name** | **Purpose** | **More information**  
---|---|---|---  
Session Cookie | PHPSESSID | This session cookie is essential for the indentification of a user on TJS Marketing Ltd website. This cookie is deleted when you close your browser. |   
  
### Schedule 2. Third-Party Cookies

**Cookie** | **Name** | **Purpose** | **More information**  
---|---|---|---  
Google Analytics | _utma _utmb _utmc _utmz DSID IDE | These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where vistors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. | [Click here for an overview of privacy at Google](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html "Google Privacy")  
Statcounter | __cfduid is_unique is_visitor_unique  | These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where vistors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. | [Click here for an overview of privacy at Statcounter](https://statcounter.com/about/legal/ "Statcounter Privacy")  
  
We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here.](http://www.networkadvertising.org/)

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google's use of the [DART cookie](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/faq.aspx) enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our sites and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). 

The search box on this web site ("Search Box") is powered by Google Inc ("Google"). You acknowledge and agree that Google's privacy policy (located at <http://www.google.co.uk/privacy.html>) shall apply to your use of the Search Box and by using the Search Box you consent to Google using your personal data in accordance with its privacy policy. 

### How to reject cookies

There are two ways you can minimise the number of cookies you receive:

**1\. Adjust your browser settings to reject cookies** (for mobile phones you will have to refer to your handset manufacturer's help manual) using one of the following procedures (depending on your website browser);

### If you're using Internet Explorer 6.0 or 7.0:

  1. Choose Tools, then
  2. Internet Options
  3. Click the Privacy tab
  4. Click on Custom Level
  5. Click on the 'Advanced' button
  6. Check the 'override automatic cookie handing' box and select Accept, Block or Prompt for action as appropriate. 

### If you're using Firefox 2.0:

  1. Choose Tools, then
  2. Options
  3. Click the Privacy icon

### If you're using Firefox 1.0 or 1.5:

  1. Choose Tools, then
  2. Options
  3. Click the Privacy icon
  4. Click the Cookies tab

### If you're using Opera 8.0 or 9.0:

  1. Choose Tools, then
  2. Preferences
  3. Advanced
  4. Cookies

### If you're using Opera 7.0:

  1. Choose File, then
  2. Preferences
  3. Privacy

### If you're using Netscape 6.0:

  1. Choose Edit, then
  2. Preferences
  3. Click on Advanced
  4. Click on Cookies

### If you're using Internet Explorer 5.0 or 5.5:

  1. Choose Tools, then
  2. Internet Options
  3. Click the Security tab
  4. Click on Custom Level
  5. Scroll down to the sixth option to see how cookies are handled by IE5 and change to Accept, Disable, or Prompt for action as appropriate.

### If you're using Internet Explorer 4.0:

  1. Choose View, then
  2. Internet Options
  3. Click the Advanced tab
  4. Scroll down to the yellow exclamation icon under Security and choose one of the three options to regulate your use of cookies.

### If you're using Internet Explorer 3.0:

  1. Choose View, then
  2. Options
  3. Click on Advanced
  4. Click on the button that says Warn before Accepting Cookies.

### If you're using Netscape Communicator 4.0:

  1. Choose Edit, then
  2. Preferences
  3. Click on Advanced
  4. Set your options in the box that says Cookies.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use information (not including your name, address email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here.](http://www.networkadvertising.org/)

### Links to other websites

Our website contains links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

### Controlling your company or personal information

You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your company or personal information in the following ways:

  * whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that indicates you agree to our terms and privacy policy, if not, do not submit the form

  * if you have previously agreed to us using your personal or company information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by writing to or emailing us at tj@uksbd.co.uk

We may occasionaly pass on your company and personal information to third parties and also if required by law. We may also use your company or personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting.

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please write to Terry Simmonds

6 Granby Road   
Honington   
Shipston-on-Stour   
Warwickshire   
CV36 5AB   

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct or delete any information found to be incorrect.

**Protecting your privacy**

At UK Small Business Directory, we’re committed to protecting your privacy and creating the controls you need to feel confident sharing with your neighbours. To reflect the new standards established by the EU’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), we’ve made updates and improvements to our service.

**Updates to our Privacy Policy and Member agreement**

In support of the these data protection rules across Europe, we’ve updated our Privacy Policy and Terms and Conditions. These changes will go into effect on 25 May, 2018. 

**Rights under GDPR.**  
The upcoming General Data Protection Regulation expands your existing set of rights regarding your personal data. These include the ability to withdraw your consent, the right to correction, and the right to be forgotten. 

**Clearer controls.**  
We made it easier to edit or delete your information on UK Small Business Directory.  
Your listing has a unique reference number which is displayed with your listing, simply quote this number when contacting us to edit or delete your information

**Our continued commitment**

Beyond updating our policies, we’re continuing to make additional efforts to respect the rights of our members. These include the following changes in the EU: 

Increasing the minimum age members can sign up to 18  
Making the choices members have clearer,  
Appointing a Data Protection Officer, to ensure that privacy remains central to our mission

If you have any questions about our efforts to comply with GDPR regulations and protect your rights, please contact our team.

**Controlling your settings**

You’re in control of your information on UK Small Business Directory and can modify your preferences at any time by contacting us.

**Why we collect your data**

We store contact details of companies who are registered on our database. This information appears in business listings on TJS Marketing websites for the purpose of enabling visitors to our websites to get in touch with you directly. 

**How we collect your data**

We do this in a number of ways, including when you share your information with us to create an account and add a listing to our directories.

**We treat your data with the utmost care and take appropriate steps to protect it.**

Some of the information you have provided may contain personal information (e.g. your home postal or email address). You can check what information we hold on your company and make any updates by contacting us and quoting your reference number

**When we’ll share your data**

Information that you submit when adding a business listing use is made publically available on our websites for the reason mentioned above. We may also share your information with others as agreed to in our terms and conditions

As part of a sale of our assets or a merger of our company: We may in the future sell all or part of our assets or be involved in a merger. It is customary for user information to be included with the transferred assets in these types of transactions. However, we will take steps to assure that any personal information is used in a manner consistent with the terms under which it was collected.

**You have certain rights, which include:**

the right to obtain access to your personal data (what personal data of yours we holds)

the right to request the deletion or removal of personal data where we are not otherwise entitled to  
retain and process such data and there is no compelling reason for its continued processing

the right to restrict or suppress the processing of your personal data, in certain circumstances. Further information is available upon request

the right to withdraw consent at any time, where relevant

the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority (the Information Commissioner’s Office).

If you wish to exercise any of these rights, please contact us for details of how an application may be made.

## Contact the UK Small Business Directory

The UK Small Business Directory is a division of TJS Marketing Ltd. a company registered in England and Wales (company no. 11426930) TJS Marketing Ltd. are registered under the Data Protection act with the registration number * For further information, please contact Mr.T J Simmonds.

Our registered address is;

6 Granby Road   
Honington   
Shipston-on-Stour   
Warwickshire   
CV36 5AB   

and our business address is;

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please contact us as soon as possible, and we will endevour to correct or delete any information found to be incorrect. 

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. If you would like a copy of the information held on you*. 

Any editing or updating of information related to directory listings is free of charge within the first 7 days of date of approval. 

Any editing or updating of information related to directory listings is free of charge after the first 7 days of date of approval at our discretion. 

Any editing or updating of information related to directory listings after 7 days of date of approval carries an admin charge of £30.00 

Directory listing deletions are free of charge at all times. 

*To process a subject access request under the Data Protection Act, we will require: 

1\. --------- 

2\. Proof of the your identity. 

This must be 1 of; 

Passport  
Photo driving license  
National identity card  
Birth certificate 

and also 1 of; 

Utility bill showing current home address  
Bank statement  
Building society statement/book 

Please do not send original documents. 

We may also need to contact you for clarification of the information you are requesting, and to agree how to send your personal data to you. 

After we have received your request, the fee and proof or your identity, the process to provide you with information can take up to 1 month 

This website contains 3rd party Advertising provided by Google Inc.

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google's use of the [DART cookie](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/faq.aspx) enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our sites and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). 

Please visit the Google Partners Privacy Information page for further information - <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/>

Name and contact details of our organisation   
TJS Marketing Ltd.   
6 Granby Road   
Honington   
Shipston-on-Stour   
Warwickshire   
CV36 5AB 

Name and contact details of your representative   
Terry Simmonds 

The contact details of your data protection officer   
Terry Simmonds.   
6 Granby Road   
Honington   
Shipston-on-Stour   
Warwickshire   
CV36 5AB   
tj@uksbd.co.uk 

The purposes of the processing   
To display in our business directory 

The lawful basis for the processing   
To display in our business directory and allow you to edit or delete 

The legitimate interests for the processing   
To display in our business directory and allow you to edit or delete 

The details of transfers of the personal data to any third countries or international organisations   
Information is made publically available Online, anyone worldwide can view the information you provide 

The retention periods for the personal data   
All information you submit will be retained until you ask us to delete it 

The rights available to individuals in respect of the processing   
You can ask us to delete or edit your information at any time 

The right to withdraw consent   
You can ask us to delete or edit your information at any time 

The right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority   
You can lodge a complaint at any time 

The details of the existence of automated decision-making, including profiling   
Any information you provide may be automatically displayed online
